Hi everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
In today's lesson, we're going to learn about
a question type of the IELTS listening section
1.
It is form filling.
This is the easiest question type in the
IELTS listening test.
So, in this lesson, I'm going to show
you how to get a maximum score for
this type by identifying some distractors in the
IELTS listening test.
Let's get started.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the format and key features of form completion
questions, understand and apply effective steps to answer
form completion questions, learn to avoid common mistakes
including errors with phone numbers, spelling, names, and
money and finally, practice listening carefully for details
to improve accuracy in filling forms.
By the end of this lesson, you'll feel
more confident to tackle form completion questions and
achieve perfect scores.
We're going to start section 1 with the
listening test.
In this part, you will listen to a
conversation and fill in the form of 10
questions.
The topics are often about situations in daily
life.
For example, register for a course or book
a hotel.
Since 2020, you will no longer hear the
example at the beginning of section 1.
For this part, you need to write some
personal information such as telephone numbers, addresses, hobbies,
occupations, qualifications, or experience.
This is the easiest section of the IELTS listening test.
After listening, you will have 30 seconds to
check your answer.
Form filling, note completion, and summary completion have
the following things in common.
Candidates need to identify missing words in the
recording and follow the questions requirement.
Do not change the part of speech of
words to be filled in.
You should read the requirement carefully because if
your answers exceed the word limit, they won't
be scored.
In the second part, we're going to learn
about how to handle the form filling questions.
Step 1.
Before listening, you need to read the requirement
to identify the word.
Step 2.
You need to read the title to understand
the topic of the recording.
Then, read questions and underline keywords because these
keywords can help you locate which part speakers
are talking about.
Step 3.
After that, you need to predict what type
of information is missing from each blank.
Moreover, you can also predict some paraphrases of
the keywords so you can listen in an
active way.
Remember that when making predictions, we need to
base on grammatical structures and the context of
conversations.
Moreover, we need to predict some distractors in the
recording.
For example, when you listen to numbers, the
distractors are often about some numbers ending with
T or teen.
And when you listen to postcodes, you often
confuse the letter A with the number 8.
Making predictions will help us prepare well before
taking the test.
Step 4.
You will listen to the recording and write
the answers in the blanks.
Step 5.
After listening, you need to check the answers.
You have to check spellings, meanings of the
words, and verify whether the answers match the predictions.